Finding Aid for the John Povey Papers LSC.0452
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series III: African Arts, 1965-1992; 5 boxes (2.5 linear ft.)
  - Art sale correspondence., 1984-1985; (4 items). (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Letters re Frank McEwen's Shona sculptures.
  - African Art--Manuscripts., 1984; (4 items). (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Unpublished manuscript on African art.
  - Contemporary African art., 1971-1989; (ca. 25 items). (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Articles, essays, and clippings on contemporary African art.
  - Contemporary art lecture., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Notes for art lecture.
  - Conferences and symposia (1 of 2)., 1966-1990; (7 items). (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Printed material from conferences and symposia.
  - Conferences and symposia (2 of 2)., 1972-1991; (14 items). (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Printed material, especially on Warner Robbins Symposium (founder of the Smithsonian's African Art museum).
  - da Passano, M. Giovanna Paradi., 1984; (2 items). (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Essays, slides, and correspondence.
  - Galleries (1 of 3)., 1988-1990; (ca. 40 items). (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Correspondence and gallery publications.
  - Galleries (2 of 3)., 1969-1992; (ca. 30 items). (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Galleries (3 of 3)., 1967-1991; (ca. 30 items). (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Various exhibition programs.
  - Horniman Museum., 1987-1990; (11 items). (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Museum publications.
  - Nigerian art., 1988-1991; (18 items). (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Assorted printed material on art and artist Tayo Adenaike.
  - Paris art project., 1989-1991; (11 items). (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Various correspondence on anti-apartheid art project.
  - Publishing files., 1965-1991; (ca. 20 items). (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Publisher correspondence.
  - Shona art (1 of 7)., 1988; (25 items). (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Assorted printed material on Shona art and on artist Sylvester Mubayi.
  - Shona art (2 of 7)., 1974-1990; (21 items). (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Assorted printed materials on Shona art.
  - Shona art (3 of 7)., 1980-1988; (15 items). (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Shona art (4 of 7)., 1990; (7 items). (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Shona art (5 of 7)., 1985-1990; (17 items). (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Shona art (6 of 7)., 1983-1990; (17 items). (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Assorted printed materials on Shona art, including publications from the National Gallery of Zimbabwe.
  - Shona art (7 of 7)., 1989-1991; (28 items). (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Studio Museum., 1989; (7 items). (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Assorted printed materials from the Studio Museum.
  - Theatre and drama., 1965-1969; (32 items). (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Printed materials on West African plays.
  - Universita Internazionale Dell'Arte., 1984-1989; (11 items). (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Various materials on Universita Internazionale Dell'Arte.
  - World Festival of Negro Arts., 1966-1967; (12 items). (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Brochures and printed materials on the World Festival of Negro Arts.
    See Box 36 for oversized material.
- Series IV: Publications and Manuscripts, 1960-1991; 8 boxes
  Series IV consists John F. Povey's publications, and the publications of his colleagues and students.
  It is organized into two subseries:
  Subseries IVA: Publications by John Povey, 1965-1991
  Subseries IVB: Publications by others, 1966-1991
  Books in Collection 452 have been individually cataloged. They are discoverable in the UCLA Library online catalog by keyword searching the phrase: "ex libris John Povey."
  - Subseries IVA: Publications by John Povey, 1965-1991
    - Achebe and Bladwin in C.B. Land., 1980; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Achebe's War Poetry., 1980; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Africa through African Eyes., 1976; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - African Art in the Classroom., 1969; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - African Artist in a Traditional Society., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - African Literature., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - African Literature in Paperback., 1976; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - African Literature's Widening Range., 1969; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - African Writer and Commitment., (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Afro-American and African Literature in English: Discipline, Deportment and Theme., (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - American Education and French Assimilation., (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - "Anger Congeals and Becomes Aware.", (2 items). (Box 26, Folder 12)
      Poem by Dennis Brutus.
    - Beginnings of an English Language Literature in East Africa., 1970; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Black Gods and Kings., ca. 1972; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Book reviews., 1965-1990; (ca. 75 items). (Box 26, Folder 15)
      Book reviews from various journal sources.
    - Burgeoning Literature of the New African States., 1966; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Canons of Criticism for Neo-African Literature., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Changing Themes in the Nigerian Novel., 1966; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - The Classic., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Conference on South African Writing., 1969; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Contemporary African art., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Contemporary West African Writing in English., 1966; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Criticism of African Literature., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Cyprian Ekwensi and Beautiful Feathers., 1965; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Dakar: An African Rendez-vous., 1966; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Dennis Brutus: Poetry and Politics., 1973, 1986; (2 items). (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Development of International Programs., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Education in African Writers., 1966; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - English in French Speaking Africa., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - English Language in Africa., 1966; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - English Language Poetry., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - English Language of the Contemporary...., 1969; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - English Like Pearl Buck., ca. 1978; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - English Writers in Africa., 1974; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Epitaph to Christopher Okigbo., 1967; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - First World Festival of Negro Arts at Dakar., 1966; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Gentlest Bonds., 1977; (2 items). (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Hearts Country., 1986; (2 items). (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Higher Education in Britain Since 1945., ca. 1960; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - I Am the Voice., ca. 1981; (2 items). (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Integrating Non-Western Materials...., 1984; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Introduction., 1984; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - J.M. Coetzee., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Landscape in Early South African Poetry., ca. 1960; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Language Education, Language Acquisition., 1991; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Language Policy and Language Teaching., 1980; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Language of Soweto Poetry., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Lenrie Peters., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Literature for Discussion., 1984; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Literature in TESL Programs., 1967; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - A Lyre of Savage Thunder., 1966; (1 item). (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - The Man Died., 1974; (2 items). (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Morality and Distance in Achebe., (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Myrrh of Parting., 1966; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Negritude., 1986; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - New British Universities., 1972; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - The Nigerian War., ca. 1966; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Novels of Chinua Achebe., 1970; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Novels of Onora Nzekwu., 1968; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Onitsha Market Books., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Oyono's Ironic Vision., 1985; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Poetry of Mafika Gwala., 1986; (3 items). (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Political Theme in South and West...., 1969; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Politics and the South African Novel., ca.1975; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Political Vision of the West African Writer., ca. 1969; (2 items). (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Poor Waifs Upon Creation's Skirts., 1967; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Profile of an African Artist: Dennis Brutis., 1967; (1 item). (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - The Quality of African Writing Today., 1968; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Regional Preferences in African Art., 1984; (2 items). (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Retrospect Attempts to Build an African Literature., n.d.; (2 items). (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Robert Frost, the American Poet., 1976; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Role of the African Poet., 1977; (2 items). (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Roy Campbell., 1977; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Search for Identity in Edward Braithwaite...., ca. 1973; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Second Language Literatures., 1971; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Some Observations for the Commercial...., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - South African Literature., n.d.; (2 items). (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - South African Writing., ca. 1972; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Styles and Themes in the African Novel., 1970; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Teaching Literature in South Africa., 1980; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Untitled (1 of 2)., ca. 1968; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Untitled (2 of 2)., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Victory of Magic in Two Novels...., ca. 1968; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - West African Drama in English., 1967; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Wole Soyinka and the Nigerian Drama., 1966; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Wole Soyinka., ca. 1966; (1 item). (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Subseries IVB: Publications by Others, 1966-1991
    - Abdallah, Mohammed ben., 1972; (1 item). (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Ananse and the Golden Drum.
    - Abdallah, M. Ibn., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 30, Folder 2)
      Verdict of the Cobra.
    - Anyidoho, Kofi., 1972; (1 item). (Box 30, Folder 3)
      The Things I Have to Say.
    - Berlyn, Phillippa., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 30, Folder 4)
      The Little Beer Pot: An Anthology of Translations fro the Shona Poets.
    - Brokensha, David., 1969-1975; (2 folders, 25 items in each folder). (Box 30, Folder 5-6)
      Unfinished manuscript and notes from African Art professor Brokensha and Povey.
    - Coker, Syl Cheyney., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 30, Folder 7)
      Tom Tom Poems.
    - Cordor, S. Henry., ca. 1984; (1 item). (Box 30, Folder 8)
      Making an African Mountain Talk.
    - Euba, Femi., 1976; (1 item). (Box 30, Folder 9)
      Cornucopia.
    - Farah, Nuruddin., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 30, Folder 10)
      A Naked Needle.
    - Gerbault, Jeannine., 1979; (1 item). (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Gibbs, Marianne., 1987; (1 item). (Box 31, Folder 2)
      The Lappish Language.
    - Giltmier, Jim., 1968-1969; (40 items). (Box 31, Folder 3)
      Book notes on an unfinished manuscript.
    - Glasco, Laurence A., 1987; (2 items). (Box 31, Folder 4)
      The African Heritage Classroom at the University of Pittsburgh, Concept, Design and Symbols.
    - Hardin, Deborah., 1986; (1 item). (Box 31, Folder 5)
      Indian Elements in R.K. Narayan's: The Bachelor of Arts.
    - Jahadhmy, Ali A., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 31, Folder 6)
      The Eye Full of Love.
    - Johnson, Lemuel., 1976; (1 item). (Box 31, Folder 7)
      The Resurrectionist's Post-Mortem.
    - Kachru, Braj B., 1978; (1 item). (Box 31, Folder 8)
      The Pragmatics of Non-Native Varieties of English.
    - Kelly, Kathleen., ca. 1986; (1 item). (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Lesson Plan for Teaching Literature to ESL Students.
    - Ma'Hall, Bill., 1965; (1 item). (Box 31, Folder 10)
      The Son of Umbele.
    - Mbangwana, Paul., 1985; (2 items). (Box 31, Folder 11)
      Copy of typed correspondence from Mbangwana and article.
    - Mistry, Ketna., 1991; (1 item). (Box 31, Folder 12)
      Nuruddin Farah's From a Crooked Rib: A Search for Identity.
    - Moore, Bai T., 1967; (1 item). (Box 31, Folder 13)
      Murder in the Cassada Patch.
    - Oknaku, Joseph O.O., 1966-1967; (2 items). (Box 32, Folder 1)
      The King's Son
      The Virtues of Adultery
    - Ola, Virginia., 1984; (2 items). (Box 32, Folder 2)
      Iska Revisited.
      Also, letter.
    - Osahon, Naiwu., n.d.; (2 items). (Box 32, Folder 3)
      A Little Darkness
      The Climate of Darkness
    - Peters, Jonathan A., ca. 1986; (1 item). (Box 32, Folder 4)
      Copy of text Ousmane Sembene, Contemporary Griot.
    - Ruiz, Jean Marie., 1987; (1 item). (Box 32, Folder 5)
      The Basque Language in Spain.
    - Saul, Wendy., 1987; (1 item). (Box 32, Folder 6)
      The Hungarian Language in Romania.
    - Sellin, Eric., 1971; (1 item). (Box 32, Folder 7)
      Negritude: Status or Dynamics?
    - Sherwin, Kitty., 1980; (2 items). (Box 32, Folder 8)
      Drums and Bare Feet.
    - Smith-Pearse., 1968; (1 item). (Box 32, Folder 9)
      The English Errors of Indian Students.
    - Tapia, Catherine., 1985; (1 item). (Box 33, Folder 1)
      National Language Policy in Singapore.
    - Taylor, Richard., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 33, Folder 2)
      Ezeulu: A Nok Play.
    - Tejani, Bahadur., n.d.; (1 item). (Box 33, Folder 3)
      Okello's Shakespeare.
    - Unidentified (1 of 2)., n.d.; (2 items). (Box 33, Folder 4)
      Novel manuscript
      2 leaves of unidentified prose
    - Unidentified (2 of 2)., ca. 1983; (4 items). (Box 33, Folder 5)
      Short stories manuscripts:
      Goodbye Mama!, A Voice in the Wind
      "Reflection" (poem, photocopies)
      Letter to Povey from Lester P. Monts of UCLA's Department of Ethnomusicology
    - Vanniurdjan, Swathi (1 of 2)., 1983; (10 items). (Box 33, Folder 6)
      Original book notes and unfinished manuscript.
    - Vanniurdjan, Swathi (2 of 2)., 1983; (25 items). (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Wright, Derek., 1975-1977; (2 items). (Box 33, Folder 8)
      The Chaka Syndrome
      Ritual and Reality in Four West African Novelists
    - Okpewbo, Isidore., ca. 1960; (1 item, oversize bound manuscript). (Box 36)
      The Last Duty.
- Series V: Miscellaneous Professional Papers, 1968-1992; 2 boxes
  Series V consists of miscellaneous correspondence, applications, grant proposals, and budget files, including materials related to the Center for African Studies.
  - African Dance., 1979-1980; (8 items). (Box 34, Folder 1)
    Various printed materials on summer dance program.
  - African Humanities Institute (1 of 2)., 1978-1979; (2 items). (Box 34, Folder 2)
    Proposal for UCLA--AHI.
  - African Humanities Institute (2 of 2)., 1979; (3 items). (Box 34, Folder 3)
    Dossier on John Povey and application for AHI funding.
  - African Studies., 1968-1990; (5 items). (Box 34, Folder 4)
    Assorted printed material on African Studies.
  - African Studies--Project., 1969-1980; (18 items). (Box 34, Folder 5-6)
    Various printed materials on school project.
    - 1969-1980, (18 items). (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - 1969, (4 items). (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - African visitors., 1981-1987; (15 items). (Box 34, Folder 7)
    File on African visitors to the U.S.
  - Contracts/Grants., 1978-1991; (16 items). (Box 34, Folder 8)
    Various printed budget/contract materials.
  - Correspondence--Africa., 1974-1991; (32 items). (Box 34, Folder 9)
    Assorted correspondence.
  - Correspondence--India., 1982-1985; (12 items). (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--Miscellaneous., 1970-1990; (12 items). (Box 34, Folder 11)
    Assorted correspondence and notes.
  - English Abroad Program., 1984-1989; (19 items). (Box 35, Folder 1)
    EAP related printed materials.
  - Miscellaneous., 1974-1992; (35 items). (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - NEH-AHI file., 1975-1979; (4 items). (Box 35, Folder 3)
    Continuation proposal.
  - NEH., 1975-1980 (Box 35, Folder 4-6)
    Application material.
    - 1979-1980, (2 items). (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - 1975-1979, (13 items). (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - 1975, (4 items). (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Publishing files., 1989-1991; (22 items). (Box 35, Folder 7)
    Correspondence and materials from publishers.
  - Recommendations., 1972-1991; (23 items). (Box 35, Folder 8)
    Various letters of recommendation by Povey.
  - South African Fellows., 1990-1991; (5 items). (Box 35, Folder 9)
    Various printed materials on SAF.
  - Teaching Abroad--East Africa., 1970; (5 items). (Box 35, Folder 10)
    Various printed material.
  - UCLA--Extension., 1981-1991; (ca. 15 items). (Box 35, Folder 11)
    Various printed material on UCLA extension.
  - UCLA--Linkage., 1982; (8 items). (Box 35, Folder 12)
    Printed materials on Cuttington/UCLA linkage.
  - Wodehouse Society., 1990-1991; (10 items). (Box 35, Folder 13)
    Various printed materials from the literary society.